格丽泽尔达
Griselda.
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译  森の鸟
翻译  蘑菇
翻译  Reginamoon
翻译  重案组李Sir
翻译  小饭
翻译  冰蓝
翻译  33来了
校对  卫老哥
校对  冰蓝  送小孩
时间轴  冰蓝  涛涛
时间轴  鸟の森
后期  、青衣
特效/后期  送小哥
总监  送小孩
行尸走肉
第四季  第十四集
你可以睡觉  丽兹  我没事
You can sleep, Lizzie. I'm okay.
如果有危险  我可以照顾朱迪思
If there's trouble, I can take Judith.
我能帮忙
I can help.
你真觉得能帮我吗
You really think you can help me?
我知道我可以  女士
I know I can, ma'am.
你觉得那里会有孩子吗
Do you think there'll be kids there?
在终点站
At Terminus?
如果他们的家长保护他们  就会有
If their parents kept them safe.
就像泰尔西保护了你们一样
Like Tyreese kept all of you safe.
我救了泰尔西
I saved Tyreese.
有人对他开枪
There were people shooting at him.
我开枪杀了他们
I shot them.
首先是个男人  然后是个女人
First a man, then a woman.
我本来不想打中她的头的
I didn't mean to shoot her in the head.
你必须这样做
You had to.
你救了泰尔西
You saved Tyreese.
也许那里会有小孩
Maybe there'll be kids there,
就算他们的家长没能保护他们
even if their parents couldn't keep them safe.
也许是小孩保护了家长
Maybe the kids kept their parents safe.
是啊
Yeah.
你有孩子吗
Did you have kids?
有过
I did.
一个孩子
A kid.
女儿
A daughter.
她是什么样子啊
What was she like?
她很可爱
She was sweet.
她天生就心地善良
She didn't have a mean bone in her body.
所以她没活下来吗
Is that why she isn't here now?
是的
Yeah.
你想她吗
Do you miss her?
每天都想
Every day.
你会想我吗
Would you miss me?
我没必要想你
I'm not gonna have to miss you.
你累坏了
You're dead on your feet.
去你妹妹旁边睡吧  好吗
Go sleep next to your sister, okay?
但是  女士  我可以帮忙
But, ma'am, I can help.
明天我需要你帮忙做事
I'm gonna need your help looking after things tomorrow.
去睡觉  好吗
Go to sleep, okay?
去吧
Go.
不
No.
不不
No, no.
不不不
No, no. No.
找到了
Found some.
是啊  干得好
There you go. Good job.
-很疼  对吗  -是的  很疼
- It hurts, right? - Oh, yeah. It hurts.
这会消炎
This will fight the infection.
可能还会让你退烧
Might even bring down your fever.
你怎么看
What do you think?
还要走三天  还是四天
Three days out? Four days?
我们在十字路口没看见地图
We haven't seen any of those maps at the crossings.
我不确定
I'm not sure.
丽兹心狠手辣
Lizzie's tough.
那是对人类
When it comes to people.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
你没看到吗
You haven't seen it?
她把行尸搞混了
How she's confused about them, the walkers.
她没有看出它们的本质
She doesn't see what they are.
觉得它们只是不一样
She thinks they're just different.
米卡也是这样吗
Mica the same way?
不  她更糟
No, she's worse.
她太善良了
She doesn't have a mean bone in her body.
《汤姆・索耶历险记》的结局好吗
Did "Tom Sawyer" have a happy ending?
我们还没有读完呢
We never got to finish it.
汤姆和哈克
Well, Tom and Huck,
阻止了印江・乔埃和他的同伴
they stop Injun Joe and his partner
然后拿到了他们的金子
and wind up getting all his gold.
-所以说他们最后变富翁了  -是的
- So they wind up rich? - Mm-hmm.
道格拉斯寡妇收养了哈克
And the Widow Douglas adopts Huck.
就像你收养了我们一样
Like you adopted us?
是的  就像道格拉斯寡妇一样
Yeah, just like the Widow Douglas.
而我是哈克・费恩
And I'm Huck Finn.
我觉得你更像汤姆・索耶
I think you're more like Tom Sawyer.
汤姆比较孩子气  哈克则坚强冷静
是啊  你说得对
Yeah, you're right.
你更像哈克・费恩
You're way more like Huck Finn.
死兔子都没有恶心到你
You're not even grossed out by dead rabbits.
我都忘了你以前会给他们读故事了
Forgot you used to read to them.
是啊
I did.
-你闻到了吗  -闻到了
- You smell that? - Yeah.
有地方着火了
There's a fire somewhere.
肯定是场大火  这附近没有着火
Must be a big one. It isn't anywhere around here.
我们应该停下来  找点水
We should stop here. We need to look for water.
我去找
I can do it.
不  你需要休息  让胳膊休息一下
No, you need rest. Rest your arm.
米卡会帮我的
Mica will help me.
我看到了树跟草
I spy trees and weeds.
该你了
Your turn.
给你  待着别动
Here. You stay here.
泰尔西
Tyreese.
有时我们必须杀了他们
Sometimes we have to kill them.
我知道  但有时我们不必
I know that. But sometimes we don't.
你知道丽兹比我力气大的
You know Lizzie can carry a lot more than me.
我让你来是因为我有话对你说
I had you come because I wanted to talk to you.
为什么
Why?
因为你很小  而且很善良
Because you're little and you're sweet
这会让你丧命
and those are two things that can get you killed.
你不能马上长大
You can't change how big you are...
我希望我能
I wish I could.
但是你可以坚强起来
...but you can toughen up.
我不必变坚强
I don't have to be tough.
我可以跑  我跑得很快
I can run. I'm good at that.
不行
No.
我女儿也会跑  但是这不够
My daughter ran and it wasn't enough.
所以在监狱里我教孩子们别的技能
That's why I taught the kids at the prison to do more than that.
我可以杀行尸
I can kill walkers.
我是说  我试过
I mean, I've tried.
我跟我姐姐不一样  我心理很正常
I'm not like my sister. I'm not messed up.
我知道行尸是什么
I know what they are.
但是我不能杀人
But I can't kill people.
我下不了手
I could never do that.
那些坏人来到监狱的时候
When the bad people were at the prison,
他们就在我们面前
they were right in front of us
我举起枪
and I held up my gun,
但是我没能按下扳机
but I couldn't pull the trigger.
杀人是不对的
Killing people is wrong.
有人杀了凯伦和大卫
Someone killed Karen and David.
就那样把他们杀了  他们人很好
They just killed them. They were nice.
那有人要杀你怎么办
What about people who try to kill you?
那我也不希望杀人
I don't even wish I could.
那些人闯进来杀了我们的朋友
People came in and killed our friends.
我同情那些人
And I feel sorry for them.
为什么
Why?
因为他们以前八成不是这样的
Because they probably weren't like that before.
你迟早得这么做的
Sooner or later you're gonna have to do it.
你必须这么做  不然你就会死
You'll have to do it or you'll die.
所以你得改变你的想法
So you're gonna change the way you think about it.
你必须改变  每个人都变了
You have to change. Everyone does now.
事情不会自己变好的
Things don't just work out.
看
Look.
我妈曾说过
My mom used to say
一切自有天意
everything works out the way it's supposed to.
这些是什么
What are these?
-山核桃  -我超喜欢山核桃
- Pecans. - Oh, I love pecans.
也许我们能在这儿喘口气
You know, maybe we could catch our breath here for a while.
我们还是要去终点站的  是吧
We're still going to Terminus, right?
我们只在这儿待个一两天
We'll just stay a day or two.
这儿有满满一井水
There's a well full of water.
有围栏  虽然不是很高  但也能挡一下
Fences. They're not big, but they're something.
而且我们之前看到鹿了  它们吃山核桃
And we saw deer. They eat pecans.
我们应该能打到一只来吃
We should be able to kill one to eat.
我们也能吃山核桃吧  对吗
We can eat these, too, right?
你可以吃个饱
You can eat your fill and then some.
看
Look.
那肯定就是我们刚刚闻到的东西
Bet that's what we were smelling.
看起来够远的
Looks far enough away.
我想知道是怎么烧起来的
I wonder how it started.
也许是闪电  也许是营火
Maybe lightning. Maybe a campfire.
我可以去把围栏补一补
I can patch that fence.
那里八成是鹿进出的地方
It's probably where the deer are coming from.
我们应该把开口留着  给自己留条后路
We should leave it. Just play it really safe in here.
假如里面有个行尸  它还真没怎么动啊
If there's one in there, it's not moving much.
我们挨得近一点
Let's just stay close,
一间间慢慢检查
go slow room to room.
姑娘们  你们好好待着
Girls, you sit tight.
在我们出来前你们别进来
You don't come in until we come out
无论你们听到了什么
no matter what you hear.
-好的  -好的
- Okay. - Okay.
丽兹抱着朱迪思呢  米卡把你的枪拿出来
Lizzie's got Judith. Mica, get out your gun.
你得站岗
You're gonna need to stand watch.
坚强点  小姑娘
Stand strong, little lady.
他们不会有事的
They're gonna be okay.
我不是在想那个
It's not that.
是因为那里埋了个婴儿吗
Is it that there was a baby?
不是
No.
他们会在里面发现一个行尸  然后...
They're gonna find one in there and they're going--
别说了  它们已经不是人了
Stop it. They aren't people.
但是你错了  所有人都错了
But you're wrong. All of you.
它们不是人  丽兹  它们是死人
They aren't people, Lizzie. They're just dead.
住手  住手  住手
Stop! Stop! Stop!
你没事吧
Are you okay?
没事了  来吧  起来吧
All right, come on. Come on.
来吧  来吧  我抱住你了  小姑娘
Come on, come on. I got you, little girl.
-好了  来吧  -米卡
- Come on. Come here. - Mica.
米卡  把枪放下
Mica, lower the gun.
你做到了  你救了她们
You did it. You saved them.
你为什么这么难过  丽兹  你被吓到了吗
Why are you upset, Lizzie? Were you scared?
不是
No.
那你为什么哭
Then why are you crying?
我不想说
I don't want to say.
丽兹
Lizzie.
对不起我吼你了
I'm sorry I yelled at you.
你看看这些花儿就好了
Just look at the flowers like you're supposed to.
数一二三
Count one, two, three.
来吧  我们一起数
Come on, let's count together.
瞧瞧那朵粉色的  你看到了吗
Look at the pink ones over there. You see?
一二三
One, two, three.
你还是很心烦吗
You still upset?
有时我真的不理解
Sometimes I don't understand,
但我在努力去理解  女士
but I'm trying to, ma'am.
真的
I am.
看我找到了什么
Look what I found.
我打算给她起名为格丽泽尔达・冈德森
I'm gonna name her Griselda Gunderson.
我们有很多水
Well, we got plenty of water.
现在只要再杀一头鹿就万事齐全了
Now all we got to do is bag one of them deer and we're all set.
-那就去弄一头  -好
- Then we'll get one. - Yeah.
-怎么了  -我不太习惯这样
- What's wrong? - I'm not used to this.
习惯什么
Used to what?
我们居然在一所房子的客厅里
We're in a living room in a house.
对  所以放松点
Yeah, so relax.
我们应该住在这儿
We should live here.
格丽泽尔达
Griselda.
丽兹
Lizzie.
快点
Come on.
-快离开它  -不不不
- You get away from it! - No, no, no!
-马上  丽兹  -不不不
- Right now, Lizzie. - No, no, no, no, no.
-不  不  -丽兹  丽兹
- No, no, no, no. - Lizzie! Lizzie!
不  不
No! No!
她在跟我玩  她只是想要个朋友
She was playing with me. She wanted a friend.
它是想杀了你
She wanted to kill you.
-我打算引她离开  -你差点就死了
- I was gonna lead her away. - You could have died.
一回事  你杀了她
It's the same thing! You killed her!
-你杀了她  就是一回事  -丽兹
- You killed her! It's the same thing! - Lizzie.
-如果我杀了你怎么样  -丽兹
- What if I killed you?! What if I killed you?! - Lizzie.
-你不明白  你不明白  -丽兹
- You don't understand. You don't understand. - Lizzie.
你不明白  你不懂你不懂
You don't understand. You don't understand. You don't understand!
丽兹  丽兹
Lizzie. Lizzie.
你不一定要杀她啊
You didn't have to.
没必要啊  她没想伤害谁
You didn't have to. She didn't want to hurt any...
她没想伤害任何人
She didn't want to hurt anybody!
她是我朋友  你却杀了她
She was my friend and you killed her!
你杀了她
You killed her!
她是我朋友
She was my friend.
会不会太重了
Is it too heavy?
不会  没事
Nah, I'm good.
火还在烧
The fire's still burning.
也可能熄灭了
It could have gone out.
不  烟还是黑的
Nope. The smoke's black.
如果烟是白的  火就熄灭了
If it was white, the fire wouldn't be burning anymore.
我好怀念科学课啊
I miss science class.
除了有时候我们得
Except for when we had to do stuff like
把涡虫切碎什么的
cut up planaria worms.
你现在得做更残忍的事情  米卡
You've got to do worse than that nowadays, Mica.
-不一定吧  -一定的
- I don't gotta. - You do.
丽兹比你大  她在某种程度上比你强壮
Lizzie's bigger than you and in some ways she's stronger.
但你更聪明
But you're smarter
而且你也明白这些...道理
and you understand these... things.
你得照顾她
You've got to look out for her.
你必须...
You have to--
不  来吧  你来
No, go ahead. You do it.
就像我在监狱里教你的一样  开始吧
Just like I showed you at the prison. Go ahead.
我不行
I can't.
我们还有核桃啊
We have peaches.
也许我们不必去终点站
Maybe we don't need to go to Terminus.
我想过了
I've been thinking.
米卡说得对
Mica's right.
我们可以留下
We can stay here.
在这里生活
We can live here.
我了解丽兹和米卡
I know Lizzie and Mica.
我了解朱迪斯
I know Judith.
我了解你
I know you.
也信任你
I trust you.
除你们之外  我不知道还能信任谁
And I don't know if I can get that anywhere else.
我们可以留下
We could stay.
在这里生活
We can live here.
丽兹
Lizzie?
别担心
Don't worry.
我还会来喂你的
I'll get you more.
丽兹
Lizzie.
我们给它们取名字时
When we were giving them names,
只是在假装这一切很好玩
we were just pretending things weren't bad.
其实一点不好玩
Things are bad.
这些行尸  它们很坏
Those things, they're bad. They are.
别再自欺欺人了
We can't pretend anymore.
我没有骗自己  是你在骗自己
I'm not pretending. You were.
我知道  我听得见他们的心声
I know. I can hear them.
它们想杀了你
They want to kill you.
他们只不过是想改变我
They just want me to change.
让我变得跟他们一样
They can make me be like them.
或许我应该改变
Maybe I should change.
住手
Stop it.
这样你们就明白了
I can make you all understand.
丽兹
Lizzie.
丽兹  它们来了  丽兹
Lizzie, they're coming. Lizzie!
卡萝尔
Carol!
救命
Help!
救我  卡萝儿  丽兹
Help, Carol! Lizzie!
-丽兹  -米卡
- Lizzie! - Mica!
-米卡  -丽兹
- Mica! - Lizzie!
放开我  救命
Let me go! Help me!
-救命  -躲到我们身后
- Help! - Get behind us!
没事了
It's okay.
你做到了
You did it.
我得帮忙阻止它们
I had to help stop them.
你现在知道它们是什么了吗
Do you understand what they are now?
我知道...
I know--
我知道我必须做什么了
I know what I have to do now.
我知道了
I know.
现实很丑恶  很可怕
It's ugly and it's scary
也的确会改变你
and it does change you.
一路走来  我们都变了很多
That's how we get to be here.
这就是成长的代价
That's the cost. That's growing up now.
我不想伤害任何人
I don't want to hurt anyone.
我不想当坏人
I don't want to be mean.
有时候你必须狠心
You have to be sometimes.
不过也只是有时候
But just sometimes.
不  不
No. No.
这里有很多山核桃
Now we have a lot of pecans here.
一大堆
A ton.
-吃烦了吗  -没
- You getting sick of them yet? - Nope.
我小时候  常和祖母一起做这个
I used to make these with my grandma when I was little.
闻起来真香
They smell good.
就这样  好了
There you go. All right.
我想你们可以
I think you guys are ready
开始做点饭了
to start doing the cooking around here.
谁想把它们放进去
Who wants to put 'em in?
我来
Me.
姑娘们喜欢这里
The girls like it here.
我们可以修缮一下  种些吃的
We could build it up, plant more food.
还可以找辆车  以备逃生
We could find a car for an escape route just in case.
如果你不想去终点站  我们可以留在这
If you don't want to go to Terminus, we could stay.
是的
We could.
也不是说我们永远都不去那了
It doesn't mean we can't go someday.
只不过
It's just...
当我们离终点站越来越近  我意识到
when we were getting closer and closer, i realized
我还没有做好和其他人一起生活的准备
I'm just not ready to be around other people yet.
你不用的
You don't have to.
我梦到了凯伦
I dream about Karen.
我每天晚上都会梦到她
I see her every night.
每次我都会忘记她已经死了
And every time I forget she's dead.
有时
Sometimes...
我们会说说话
we just talk.
有时
And sometimes
我看见她在人群中
I see her in the crowd...
在一个我从没去过的城市里
in a city I've never been to.
是在一切都还没有发生的时候
And it's back before everything happened.
而有的时候
And then...
有些晚上  我会做恶梦
some nights, the bad ones...
梦到有人杀了她
I see someone kill her.
某个陌生人
Some stranger.
然后我就又一次失去了她
Then I lose her all over again.
但就是这样  对吗
But that's the deal, right?
活下来的人被死去的人所纠缠
The people who are living are haunted by the dead.
我们就是这样的人
We are who we are.
我们做我们该做的事
And we do what we do
因为他们还在这里
'cause they're still here.
在我们的脑海中
In our heads.
在树林里
In the forest.
整个世界都是他们的影子
The whole world is haunted now.
我们无处可逃
And there's no getting out of that.
到死为止
Not until we're dead.
泰尔西
Tyreese.
也许他们不是在纠缠我们
Maybe they're not haunting us.
也许他们只是在教导我们
Maybe they're just teaching us.
提醒着我们
Helping remind us so--
这样我们才能接受必须做的事
so that we can live with what we have to do.
永远不要为自己感到羞耻  卡萝尔
Don't you ever be ashamed of who you are, Carol.
你为这些姑娘做了正确的事情
You did right by those girls.
你为大家做了正确的事情
You did right by everyone.
我们会抓到一只的
We'll get one yet.
也许还没到打鹿的季节
Probably not even deer season.
我丈夫以前经常打猎
My husband used to hunt.
每年都会讲同一个蠢笑话
He'd tell the same stupid joke every year.
说来听听
You gonna tell it?
话不能说半句  是吧
Well, I guess I have to now, right?
说吧
You do.
好吧
Okay.
坚果罐头和鹿睾丸有什么区别
What's the difference between beer nuts and deer nuts?
坚果罐头大约1.79美元
Beer nuts are around 1.79,
而鹿的睾丸不到1美元
deer nuts are just under a buck.
双关  鹿的睾丸在雄鹿[buck]身下
真的是好蠢
That's good stupid,
但绝对不是个好笑话
but in no way is it stupid good.
我说了嘛  还有好多这种笑话呢
Yeah, I told you. There's more where that came from.
别担心  她会醒过来的
Don't worry. She'll come back.
我没有伤到她的脑子
I didn't hurt her brain.
不  我们得等等
No, no, no! We have to wait.
我要展示给你看  你会明白
I need to show you. You'll see.
你会明白的  我们得等着
You'll finally get it. We have to wait.
丽兹  放下枪
Lizzie, put the gun down.
我只想让大家等一等
I just want us to wait.
我们能等
We can wait.
我们能等  你把枪给我
We can wait. You just give me the gun.
我们能等  我保证
We can wait, I swear.
你和泰尔西应该把朱迪斯带进屋
You and Tyreese should take Judith back.
这里对她不安全
It's not safe for her.
但朱迪斯也会变的
But Judith can change, too.
-我正打算...  -她还不会走路呢
- I was just about to-- - She can't even walk yet.
是的  你说得对
Yeah, you're right.
你们俩把朱迪斯带回屋子
So you two take Judith back to the house
然后我们吃午饭
and we'll have lunch.
我会绑住米卡
And I'll just tie Mica up.
确保她不会乱跑
You know, just so she won't go anywhere.
你保证你会那样做吗
Promise that's what you'll do?
我保证
I promise.
我会用她的鞋带绑
I'll use her shoelaces.
咱们走  丽兹
Let's-- let's go, Lizzie.
我给她带了些食物
I brought her some food.
检查了她的房间
Cleared out her room.
确保她没有刀
Made sure she doesn't have any knives,
或任何武器
anything like that.
她有一个装满老鼠的鞋盒
She has a shoe box full of mice.
我问她  是不是她在监狱给行尸喂食
I asked her if she was the one feeding the walkers at the prison.
就是她
That was her.
还有在墓地
And at the tombs,
我们找到的那只兔子
we found this rabbit
被扯得四分五裂  钉在木板上
pulled apart and nailed to a board.
也是她干的
That was her, too.
她说只是为了取乐
Said she was just having fun.
我想着
I was thinking,
也许是她杀死了凯伦和大卫
maybe she killed Karen and David.
但我不知道她怎么能把他们拖走
But I don't know how she could drag them away.
她会让他们变行尸的
She would have let them turn.
不是她杀的
It wasn't her.
我们能做什么
So what do we do?
我可以跟她离开
I could leave with her.
什么
What?
我们不能跟她和朱迪斯睡在同一屋檐下
We can't sleep with her and Judith under the same roof.
你撑不下去的  靠自己不行
You wouldn't make it. Not on your own.
她不能跟着其他人
She can't be around other people.
也许我们可以试着帮她
Maybe we could try to help her.
让她想明白
Talk her back somehow.
她就是这样的孩子
This is how she is.
已经定型了
It was already there.
我没料到
I didn't see it.
-你怎么可能料到  -我该料到的
- How could you? - I should have seen it.
还是我们走吧
So maybe we go.
我和朱迪斯
Me and Judith.
你也撑不下去的
You won't make it either.
不能让她跟着其他人
She can't be around other people.
你应该摘些野花
You should pick some wildflowers for Mica
等米卡醒来后送给她
to give her when she comes back.
好  她会喜欢的
Yeah, she'd love that.
火还在烧
The fire's still burning.
不
No.
烟是白的
The smoke's white.
已经灭了
It's out.
你什么都知道  女士
You know everything, ma'am.
不  我不知道
No, I don't.
怎么了
What is it?
你生我的气吗
Are you mad at me?
你是想跟我说这个吗
Is that what you wanted to talk to me about?
很抱歉我用枪指着你
I'm sorry I pointed my gun at you.
我只想让你等等
I just needed you to wait.
我知道
I know.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你生我气了
You're mad at me.
我爱你  丽兹
I love you, Lizzie.
一切自有天意
And everything works out the way it's supposed to.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
求求你别生我的气  我错了
Please don't be mad at me. I'm sorry.
看着花吧  丽兹
You just-- just look at the flowers, Lizzie.
看着花
Just look at the flowers.
看着花就好
Just-- just look at the flowers.
丽兹的父亲死时  卡萝尔对她说过同样的话
我杀了凯伦和大卫
I killed Karen and David.
我必须阻止疫病扩散
I had to stop the illness from breaking out.
我必须救其他人
I had to stop other people from dying.
不是丽兹
It wasn't Lizzie.
不是陌生人
It wasn't a stranger.
泰尔西  是我干的
Tyreese, it was me.
你要动手就动手吧
You do what you have to do.
你杀她时她知道吗
Did she know what was happening?
她害怕吗
Was she scared?
下手利落吗
It was quick?
是的
Yes.
你随便处置我吧
Do what you have to do.
我原谅你
I forgive you.
我永远不会忘记
I'm never gonna forget.
这事发生了
It happened.
你下的手
You did it.
你能感受到
You feel it.
我知道你能
I know you do.
这变成了你的一部分
It's a part of you now.
也是我的一部分
Me, too.
但我原谅你
But I forgive you.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们不必留下
We don't need to stay.
我们不能留下
We can't stay.
我不怕杀行尸
I'm not afraid to kill.
我只是内心害怕
I'm just afraid.
你不能害怕
You can't be.
如何做到呢
How?
去攻克它
You fight...
战胜它
and fight it.
别放弃
You don't give up.
然后某天
And then one day,
你就变了
you just change.
我们都会变
We all change.
丽兹不小心把卡萝尔叫"妈妈"后  卡萝尔对她说的话